Robert Hillyer Papers
Robert Hillyer Papers
- Literary correspondence
  - Fowler, Gene, 1941-1951; 1953-1955,; 1960,; undated; 97 Letters, 1 Telegram; 2 folders (Box 2)
    5 May 1941 - ALS Encloses newspaper article written by Fowler and comments on current literary situation in U.S. and on current political scene.
    17 Sept. 1941 - ALS Notes Timberline and remarks about Bennett Cerf.
    14 Jan. 1942 - ALS Writes of Fowler's work with motion picture studios.
    27 Jan. 1942 - ALS Mentions health difficulties of son.
    9 Nov. 1942 - TLS Mentions Hillyer's My Heart For Hostage and discusses at length Good Night, Sweet Prince.
    9 Mar. 1943 - TLS Writes at length on Hillyer's My Heart For Hostage and gives further details of Fowler's biography of Barrymore.
    13 Mar. 1943 - ALS Further mentions Heart For Hostage.
    23 Mar. 1943 - TLS Discusses possible sale of Hillyer's My Heart For Hostage to movie studios.
    2 Apr. 1943 - TLS Mentions possible attitude of Bennett Cerf towards sale of Fowler's book to movie studios.
    13 Apr. 1943 - TLS Discusses possibility of Hillyer writing an adaptation of My Heart For Hostage for Selznick.
    30 Jun. 1943 - TLS Discusses further possibility of Hollywood job.
    22 Nov. 1943 - TLS Consoles Hillyer on personal difficulties.
    8 Dec. 1943 - TLS Mentions completion of book on Barrymore and the possible legal and personal difficulties arising therefrom.
    29 Jan. 1944 - Telegram. Invites Hillyer to California.
    5 Feb. 1944 - TLS Discusses details of Hillyer's trip to California.
    9 May 1944 - TLS Expresses pleasure at Hillyer's visit.
    8 Jun. 1944 - ALS Comments on current writing assignment.
    25 Jul. 1944 - TLS Mentions Hillyer's Farrago.
    10 Aug. 1944 - ALS Thanks Hillyer for his foreword to Illusion In Java.
    17 Aug. 1944 - TLS Writes again of Hillyer's foreword to author's book.
    5 Sept. 1944 - TLS Broaches possibility of Hillyer's Harvard class criticizing Fowler's current literary work.
    1944 - ALS Discusses A Solo In Tom-Toms.
    11 Sept. 1944 - TLS Encloses foreword to A Solo In Tom-Toms for criticism by Hillyer's Harvard class.
    26 Sept. 1944 - ALS
    1944 - ALS
    2 Jan. 1945 - TLS Describes Fowler's health and refers to enclosure, a letter from Fred White which discusses Hillyer's retirement from Harvard.
    29 Jan. 1945 - TLS Mentions Hillyer's current literary activity.
    15 Feb. 1945 - TLS Encloses manuscript of A Solo In Tom-Toms for Hillyer's criticism.
    1 Mar. 1945 - Telegram. Thanks Hillyer for suggestions about above mentioned work.
    6 Mar. 1945 - TLS Discusses author's A Solo In Tom-Toms at length, with reference to Hillyer's suggestions about it.
    20 Mar. 1945 - TLS Discusses in detail some revisions of author's A Solo In Tom-Toms and encloses a copy of a letter from Fowler to his publisher noting difficulties in finishing the book and of problems involved with Barrymore book.
    23 Mar. 1945 - TLS Thanks Hillyer for his editorial comments, and describes serious incident in author's life.
    2 Apr. 1945 - TLS Comments on an ode of Hillyer's.
    6 Apr. 1945 - TLS Asks Hillyer to read revised version of author's above mentioned book.
    30 Apr. 1945 - TLS
    7 May 1945 - TLS
    17 May 1945 - TLS
    1 Jun. 1945 - TLS
    12 Jun. 1945 - TLS Describes in detail visit to Ivy Baldwin, with discussion of projected literary activity.
    23 Jun. 1945 - TLS
    11 Jul. 1945 - TLS
    24 Sept. 1945 - TLS
    8 Oct. 1945 - TLS
    7 Nov. 1945 - ALS
    3 Dec. 1945 - TLS
    12 Dec. 1945 - TLS
    17 Dec. 1945 - TLS
    4 Feb. 1946 - TLS
    21 Feb. 1946 - TLS Mentions two short stories by Hillyer, one of them "Sophia's Villa."
    30 Mar. 1946 - TLS Discusses Fowler's financial condition with mention of work projects to come.
    8 Apr. 1946 - TLS
    23 Apr. 1946 - TLS Discusses reviews of A Solo In Tom-Toms and its financial success.
    1 May 1946 - TLS
    6 May 1946 - TLS Amusingly discusses the literary implications of the "tune hit-parade."
    16 Jun. 1946 - TLS Mentions fee for Hillyer's Introduction to Illusion In Java.
    23 Sept. 1946 - ALS
    17 Oct. 1946 -
    25 Nov. 1946 - TLS Mentions Hillyer's work on a serial story.
    22 Dec. 1946 - TLS
    8 Jan. 1947 - TLS Mentions Hillyer's work on twenty- thousand-word story.
    27 Jan. 1947 - TLS Outlines current projects — Rip Van Winkle and life story of Jimmy Walker — and story of Hillyer's.
    17 Feb. 1947 - TLS
    10 Mar. 1947 - TLS Notes completion of Hillyer's book of poems.
    20 Mar. 1947 - TLS Describes meeting Robert Frost.
    27 Mar. 1947 - TLS
    4 Apr. 1947 - TLS
    10 Jun. 1947 - TLS Notes death of friend John Decker.
    23 Jun. 1947 -
    1 Aug. 1947 - TLS
    12 Aug. 1947 - TLS Congratulates Hillyer on the Hillyer issue of The Lyric and gives long appreciation of Hillyer's work.
    11 Sept. 1947 - TLS
    7 Nov. 1947 - ALS Compliments Hillyer on Poems For Music.
    13 May 1948 - TLS Discusses plans for book on life story of Jimmy Walker and encloses first two hundred pages of same for perusal by Hillyer; encloses letter to Martin Dunn of Journal-American suggesting Hillyer do some reviews for him.
    23 Sept. 1948 - ALS
    28 Sept. 1948 - ALS
    3 Nov. 1948 - TLS Encloses more chapters of book on Jimmy Walker and comments on financial condition of Hollywood and publishing.
    17 Nov. 1948 - ALS Thanks Hillyer for reading manuscript.
    22 Jan. 1949 - ALS Comments on completion of Fowler's latest book.
    23 Feb. 1949 - ALS Discusses manuscript version of The Death of Captain Nemo with specific criticisms.
    30 Aug. 1949 - TLS Mentions The Death of Captain Nemo, discusses Hillyer's Saturday Review of Literature articles on Pound and T. S. Eliot.
    27 Sept. 1949 - TLS Discusses Hillyer's move to Kenyon College.
    20 Mar. 1950 - TLS Outlines health and current literary activity.
    26 Apr. 1950 - TLS Mentions work on Jimmy Durante Story.
    18 Nov. 1950 - TLS Mentions further work on Jimmy Durante Story.
    29 Oct. 1951 - TLS Comments philosophically on lives of Fowler and Hillyer, and mentions Fowler's decision on life story of William Randolph Hearst.
    Apr. 1953 - ALS Notes beginning of new unnamed book.
    4 May 1953 - TLS Outlines new book about Sadakichi.
    Sept. 1953 - ALS
    26 Apr. 1954 - TLS
    17 May 1954 - ALS
    22 May 1954 - ALS Congratulates Hillyer on honorary degree and new position.
    30 Dec. 1955 - ALS Seeks information about Hillyer's condition after auto accident.
    4 Jan. 1960 - ALS Comments at length on personal condition and mentions new book in progress, Skyline.
    1 Jun. 1960 - TLS Comments further on Skyline.
  - Frost, Robert, 1923-1924; 1931-1932,; 1934-1935,; 1937-1938,; 1948-1950,; 1953,; 1956-1957,; 1959-1962; 16 Letters [13 Copies], 1 Telegram, 11 Printed Christmas Poems (Box 2)
    14 Apr. 1938 - ALS Requests Hillyer to be honorary bearer at funeral in Johnson Chapel, Amherst College.
    20 Apr. 1938 - Telegram. Explains above request.
    20 Feb. 1959 - TLS Suggests date for speaking engagement at University of Delaware.
    1 Jan. 1961 - ALS Thanks Hillyer for supporting him in unnamed endeavor.
    25 Jan. 1923 - Copy; Mentions Frost poem "The Census-Taker" and compliments Hillyer on his abilities.
    12 Mar. 1924 - Copy; Jokes about reading in public for Hillyer.
    26 Jul. 1924 - Copy; Mentions further public reading.
    4 Feb. 1931 - Copy; Comments on publisher's refusal to let Hillyer review author's book.
    28 Sept. 1932 - Copy; Compliments Hillyer in verse.
    5 Sept. 1934 - Copy; Comments on Hillyer's entry into the National Institute of Arts and Letters and on his Pulitzer Prize.
    23 Mar. 1935 - Copy; Refers to Hillyer's support of author in his efforts to obtain a position at Harvard.
    9 Feb. 1937 - Copy; Thanks Hillyer for coming to his rescue in unnamed event and requests help in recommending a fellowship applicant to Radcliffe.
    16 Jun. 1937 - Copy
    15 Sept. 1937 - Copy; Lengthy appreciation of Hillyer's unnamed book and promise to write more often.
    14 Apr. 1938 - Copy
    20 Jul. 1938 - Copy; Discusses difficulty of accepting Position in Harvard Latin Department while continuing as Overseer there and describes course he would like to teach.
    11 Aug. 1938 - Copy; Discusses further difficulties in teaching a course at Harvard in the Latin Department.
    Undated - Printed copy of Christmas Poem "Christmas Trees."
    Dec. 1948 - Printed copy of Christmas Poem "Closed For Good."
    Dec. 1949 - Printed copy of Christmas Poem "Holiday Greetings."
    Dec. 1950 - Printed copy of Christmas Poem "Doom To Bloom."
    4 Jul. 1953 - Printed copy of Christmas Poem "Does No One But Me Ever Feel This Way At All In The Least."
    Dec. 1956 - Printed copy of Christmas Poem "Kitty Hawk 1894."
    Dec. 1957 - Printed copy of Christmas Poem "My Objection To Being Stepped On."
    Dec. 1959 - 2 Printed Copies of Christmas Poem "A Wishing Well."
    Dec. 1960 - Printed copy of Christmas Poem "Accidentally On Purpose."
    Dec. 1962 - Printed copy of Christmas Poem "The Prophets Really Prophesy As Mystics The Commentators Merely By Statistics."
  - Frye, Burton, 1949; 2 Letters (Box 3)
    2 Sept. 1949 - ALS Supports Hillyer's position on Ezra Pound but criticizes his review concerning Mark Van Doren; with Enclosure.
    18 Nov. 1949 - TLS copy of letter from Frye to Haydon Carruth with postscript to Hillyer.
  - Garrett, Alice, 1949; 1 Letter (Box 3)
    18 Jun. 1949 - ALS Strongly compliments Hillyer on his Saturday Review of Literature articles concerning Ezra Pound and T. S. Eliot, with description of Pound's relationship to her and her husband; encloses copy of long letter from Pound to her.
  - Garrison, Frank W., 1945; 1948-1949,; 1951,; 1953-1961; undated; 45 Letters, 1 List (Box 3)
    Undated - List of Hillyer Letters to Garrison.
    Undated - TLS Comments on Hillyer's opinion of Santayana and the Victorian novelists; mentions recent reading of Byron and relates family history pertaining to that author.
    17 Sept. 1945 - Copy; Reminisces about early life and compliments Hillyer on sonnet "To A Poet Sailor" and review of Letters of Rainer Maria Rilke; comments on Albert Jay Nock and book pertaining to him.
    26 Mar. 1948 - ALS Describes landscape in literary fashion and comments on literature.
    29 Sept. 1949 - Copy; Describes trip home to California from Maine and comments further on work on book pertaining to Albert Jay Nock; compliments Hillyer on The Death of Captain Nemo.
    7 Jun. 1949 - ALS
    23 Jul. 1949 - TLS Mentions Goethe, Schweitzer, Hillyer's poem A Letter To Robert Frost and Others.
    6 Aug. 1949 - Copy; Notes receipt of Hillyer's The Death of Captain Nemo, and lauds it highly.
    29 Jul. 1951 - Copy
    8 Apr. 1953 - Copy
    26 Mar. 1954 - TL Compliments Hillyer on marriage and mentions Les Voix du Silence by Malraux and Italian Painters of The Renaissance by Berenson; mentions Hillyer's award for his poem "The Bat."
    5 Dec. 1954 - TL Points out similarity of his background to Hillyer's and describes London of 1888, 1908 and comments on American presidents.
    7 Apr. 1955 - TL
    5 Jul. 1955 - TL
    14 Oct. 1955 - TLS Mentions Joseph Jefferson.
    2 Dec. 1955 - TLS Mentions Ellen Terry, Fanny Kemble and makes philosophical observations on optimism.
    27 Jul. 1956 - ALS Discusses current reading with comments on many authors and their work.
    27 Nov. 1956 - TL Mentions George Bernard Shaw.
    4 Jun. 1957 - TL Comments on Byron and on publication of Hillyer's new unidentified volume.
    21 Nov. 1957 - TL Thanks Hillyer for copy of his book, and mentions By Love Possessed.
    5 May 1958 - TLS Reminiscences with comments about current reading of author.
    5 July 1958 - TLS Reminiscences; encloses piece entitled "The Poet of Bedford Park" on W.B. Yeats for Hillyer's use.
    23 July 1958 - TLS Mentions possibility of Hillyer writing article on W.B. Yeats.
    25 Nov. 1958 - TLS Notes current literary work of Hillyer and mentions other literary figures with short discussion of their work.
    26 Jan. 1959 - TLS Discusses Rousseau's persecution mania and mentions current literary work and reading.
    12 Feb. 1959 - TLS Mentions Hillyer column "My Civil War & Suburbia."
    13 Mar. 1959 - TL Mentions description of W.B. Yeats enclosed in earlier letter and asks if Hillyer intends to publish it.
    7 May 1959 - TLS Discusses Boris Pasternak, Aldous Huxley.
    7 July 1959 - TLS Continues discussion of Aldous Huxley at length.
    21 Aug. 1959 - TLS Relates incident concerning Sidney and Beatrice Webb and Bernard Shaw.
    14 Nov. 1959 - TLS Encloses account of mountain-climbing trip with Norbert Wiener and George Bonyoneos.
    1 Dec. 1959 - TL Mentions that he has begun reading Le Salut by DeGaulle.
    11 Jan 1960 - TLS
    3 Mar. 1960 - TLS Mentions current reading with particular comment on DeGaulle's Le Salut.
    31 May 1960 - TLS Mentions Le Salut and quotes from poem by Thomas Thorneley.
    18 June 1960 - TLS Praises The National Review and notes current reading.
    24 July 1960 - TLS
    14 Sept. 1960 - TLS Discusses economics and article in The National Review on the Congo.
    19 Oct. 1960 - TLS Comments on Hillyer's lecture on Robert Burns.
    5 Dec. 1960 - TLS Mentions Hillyer's review of book on Emily Dickinson by Jay Leyda in Times Book Review and comments on Kennedy election.
    1 Jan. 1961 - ALS Compliments Hillyer on In Pursuit of Poetry.
    21 Jan. 1961 - TLS Outlines health condition.
    12 Apr. 1961 - TLS Mentions health.
    5 May 1961 - TLS Offers to return to Hillyer all letters written by him.
    1961 - TLS
    1 Jul. 1961 - ALS Comments on Garrison's health and on President John F. Kennedy.
  - Gibson, Charles Dana, 1938; 1 Letter (Box 3)
    1 Feb. 1938 - ALS Comments on Hillyer's imminent entry into the National Institute of Arts and Letters.
  - Gogarty, Oliver St. John, 1952-1957; undated; 50 Letters (Box 3)
    4 Jun. 1952 - TLS Congratulates Hillyer on his rhyme and poetry in general; mentions Edith Sitwell.
    23 Jan. 1953 - TLS Praises in detail unnamed Hillyer book.
    28 Feb. 1953 - TLS Asks Hillyer to sit for head by Jeanne Duplaix.
    19 Mar. 1953 - TLS Schedules aforementioned sitting.
    7 Oct. 1953 - TLS Mentions Hillyer's plans to review Gogarty's Collected Poems and coming reprints of As I Was Going Down Sackville Street and It Isn't.
    12 Nov. 1953 - TLS Describes health.
    10 Dec. 1953 - TLS
    5 Jan. 1954 - TLS Relates reasons for not attending a dinner to be given by Leonora Speyer and gives Yeats' opinion of Joyce.
    16 Jan. 1954 - TLS Mentions new book, Einstein; Leonora Speyer dinner.
    6 Mar. 1954 - TLS Comments on Lord Dunsany and Theodore Weeks.
    23 Mar. 1954 - TLS Urges Hillyer to review Gogarty's Collected Poems.
    9 Apr. 1954 - TLS
    26 Apr. 1954 - TLS Mentions projected book and gives origin of its title, Start From Somewhere Else
    19 May 1954 - TLS Mentions further forthcoming publication of author's Collected Poems and It Isn't with comment on The Poetry Society of America monthly prizes.
    28 May 1954 - ALS Announces publication of Collected Poems.
    23 Jun. 1954 - ALS Sends copy of English edition of Gogarty's book of verse.
    25 Jun. 1954 - TLS Gratefully acknowledges Hillyer's review of Collected Poems and mentions negotiations for publication of Start From Somewhere Else.
    11 Jul. 1954 - TLS Notes author's Unselected Poems, a book of facetiae.
    15 Jul. 1954 - TLS Comments on Hillyer's review of Collected Poems and notes conclusion of negotiations for projected book Start From Somewhere Else.
    19 Aug. 1954 - TLS
    6 Dec. 1954 - TLS Thanks Hillyer for recommendation for $5,000.00 prize from The Poetry Society of America.
    16 Dec. 1954 - ALS Thanks Hillyer for invitation to lecture at University of Delaware.
    27 Dec. 1954 - TLS
    15 Feb. 1954 - TLS Asks that Hillyer not forget his promise to review Collected Poems for The New York Times.
    1 Mar. 1954 - TLS Mentions plan to write a book Philosophy of Drinking and tells of dispute in The Poetry Society of America over recording made of a lecture by Lord Dunsany.
    25 Mar. 1954 - ALS
    15 Jan. 1955 - ALS Condolences on the death of Hillyer's brother Stanley.
    Undated - Typed copy of author's poem "Locusts" with typed addenda.
    23 Feb. 1955 - TLS Offers to arrange to have Lord Dunsany sit for Jeanne Hillyer.
    24 Feb. 1955 - TLS Suggests name for lecture at University of Delaware and comments on Lord Dunsany.
    25 Feb. 1955 - TLS Recommends that Hillyer resign from all non-monetary appointments.
    12 Mar. 1955 - TLS Discusses Hillyer's resignation from non-monetary appointments.
    1 Apr. 1955 - TLS Comments on award of $5000.00 to Padraic Colum.
    1 Oct. 1955 - TLS Mentions Gogarty's unnamed book and Hillyer's inclusion.
    19 Nov. 1955 - ALS Notes review of unnamed Hillyer poem.
    1 Dec. 1955 - TLS Comments on publisher's policies concerning fees for poetry and amusingly describes lecture at The Library Of Congress.
    11 Dec. 1955 - ALS Quotes part of unnamed Hillyer poem and encloses A. M. Sullivan's satire on the commercialization of Christmas.
    22 Dec. 1955 - ALS
    28 Dec. 1955 - TLS Recommends that Hillyer resign immediately from Fellowship of The Academy of American Poets and inquires after details of automobile accident.
    10 Mar. 1955 - TLS Mentions sale of poem about supersonic juke-box and comments on possible change in Ode by Hillyer.
    22 Apr. 1955 - TLS Quotes poem about supersonic juke-box.
    4 May 1956 - TLS Describes Aldous Huxley lecture and mentions lectures by Hillyer on Milton's Lycidas and Davidson on Browning's The Ring And The Book.
    12 May 1956 - TLS
    8 Jun. 1956 - TLS
    14 July 1956 - ALS Asks permission to quote from Hillyer's lecture on Milton in planned address at Dublin University.
    5 Sept. 1956 - TLS Describes trip to Ireland.
    15 May 1957 - TLS Comments favorably on Hillyer's address "The Pursuit of Poetry" at Marshall College.
    19 Aug. 1957 - TLS Encloses book by Clark Kinnard.
  - Green, Theodore Francis, 1949; 1 Letter (Box 3)
    13 Aug. 1949 - ALS Thanks Hillyer for letter of August 5th concerning Fellows of American Literature of the Library of Congress and promises that the matter will be brought up at the next meeting of the Joint Committee on The Library Of Congress.
  - Gregory, Horace, 1941-1942; 1944-1945,; 1947,; undated; 10 Letters (Box 3)
    Undated - TLS Thanks Hillyer for accepting Invitation to give a reading.
    1 Apr. - ALS
    25 Mar. 1941 - TLS Requests letter of introduction to Kenneth Murdock so author may use Melville manuscript at Harvard.
    1 Apr. 1941 - TLS Notes that this request was granted.
    13 Jun. 1941 - TLS
    1 Jun. 1942 - ALS Mentions Russell Louis Award.
    31 Dec. 1944 - TLS Notes Hillyer's decision to retire.
    11 Jan. 1945 - ALS
    6 Oct. 1947 - TLS Invites Hillyer to give poetry reading at Young Men's Hebrew Association in New York City.
    1947 - ALS Notes Hillyer's acceptance of invitation to give reading.
  - Hampson, Alfred Leete, 1929; 2 Letters (Box 3)
    17 Apr. 1929 - TLS Comments on first edition of Emily Dickinson's poems, Further Poems; clipping enclosed.
    21 Mar. 1929 - ALS Describes attitude Hampson and Martha Dickinson Bianchi intend to take in editing Emily Dickinson's poems for projected work, Further Poems of Emily Dickinson.
  - Havighurst, Walter, 1948; 1956,; 1961; 4 Letters (Box 3)
    3 Feb. 1948 - TLS
    29 Mar. 1948 - TLS Mentions certain literary work of Hillyer's.
    1 Jan. 1956 - ALS
    30 Dec. 1961 - ALS Condolences from Mrs. Havighurst to Mrs. Hillyer.
  - Hay, Sally Henderson, See Lopatnikoff, Sally (Mrs. Nikolai)
  - Hergesheimer, Joseph, undated; 1 Letter (Box 3)
    Undated - ALS Conducts a long philosophical discussion of literature.
  - Hodgson, Ralph, 1945-1952; undated; 6 Letters, 13 Poems (Box 3)
    1944 - Printed copy of A Flying Scroll No. 1, a small collection of poems printed on an oblong sheet.
    1945 - Printed Copy, A Flying Scroll No. 2.
    1945 - Printed Copy, A Flying Scroll No. 3.
    1945 - Printed Copy, A Flying Scroll No. 4.
    1946 - Printed Copy, A Flying Scroll No. 5.
    1947 - Printed Copy, A Flying Scroll No. 6.
    1948 - Printed Copy, A Flying Scroll No. 7.
    1948 - Printed Copy, A Flying Scroll No. 8.
    1948 - Printed Copy, The Muse & The Mastiff, signed.
    1949 - Printed Copy, A Flying Scroll No. 9, signed.
    9 Jan. 1949 - Printed Copy, Silver Wedding and Other Poems, signed.
    1950 - Printed Copy, A Flying Scroll No. 10, signed.
    1952 - Printed Copy, A Flying Scroll No. 11, signed.
    8 Jan. 1949 - TLS Mentions Hillyer's work.
    22 Jan. 1950 - TLS
    9 Feb. 1950 - ALS Discusses Hillyer's The Death of Captain Nemo.
    17 Apr. 1951 - ALS
    22 Apr. 1951 - ALS
  - Holmes, John, 1937; 1958; 3 Letters (Box 3)
    9 Sept. 1937 - TLS Discusses Hillyer book to be published concerning Robert Frost, and recent reviews of Edna St. Vincent Millay.
    13 Sept. 1937 - TLS Further comments on Frost book, an estimation of Conrad Aiken, and a lengthy discussion of Hillyer work.
    29 Jan. 1958 - TLS Encloses picture of daughter.
  - Howard, John W., 1962; 1 Letter (Box 3)
    16 Jan. 1962 - TLS Describes causes of Hillyer's death.
  - Howe, N. A. Dew., 1929; 1936-1937; 4 Letters (Box 3)
    12 Apr. 1929 - ALS
    13 Oct. 1929 - ALS Congratulates Hillyer on Phi Beta Kappa Poem.
    3 Sept. 1936 - ALS Encloses verses for Hillyer's comment.
    27 Aug. 1937 - ALS Notes appreciation of Hillyer's work, A Letter to Robert Frost and Others.
  - Huff, Robert, 1960-1961; 6 Letters (Box 3)
    16 Nov. 1960 - TLS
    26 Jan. 1961 - TLS Discusses Hillyer's participation in Academy of American Poets Contest and mentions book of Huff, The Swinger: A Book of Dreams.
    23 Feb. 1961 - TLS Further discussion of contest and book.
    19 Apr. 1961 - TLS Encloses best entries to contest for Hillyer's judgment and mentions essay by Mark Watson.
    20 Nov. 1961 - ALS Notes regarding Academy of American Poets Prize.
    11 Dec. 1961 - ALS Relates news of Mr. Gerard Delaney, a winner of previous years Reading Poetry Prize.
  - Humphries, Rolfe, 1957; 1 Letter (Box 3)
    1957 - Mimeographed with holograph addenda. Invites Hillyer to appear in Ballantine anthology New Poems.
  - Huxley, Aldous, 1937; 1 Letter (Box 3)
    22 Apr. 1937 - ALS
  - Jeltrup, Thomas L., 1949; 1 letter (Box 3)
    15 Jun. 1949 - TLS Supports Hillyer's articles on Ezra Pound, with comparison of Pound to Dante.
  - Jensen, Johannes V., 1920-1922; 4 Letters (Box 3)
    28 Oct. 1920 - ALS Comments on Hillyer's poem.
    13 Dec. 1920 - ALS
    24 Apr. 1921 - ALS
    26 May 1922 - ALS
  - Johnson, Thomas H., 1955-1959; 25 Letters (Box 3)
    14 Sept. 1955 - ALS
    25 Sept. 1955 - TLS Comments on early Hillyer article on Emily Dickinson.
    19 Sept. 1955 - ALS
    28 Nov. 1955 - ALS Mentions Hillyer review of book on Emily Dickinson.
    4 Mar. 1956 - ALS Mentions work on Emily Dickinson letters and discusses the joys of music.
    13 Sept. 1957 - ALS Notes book of Emily Dickinson letters.
    17 Sept. 1957 - ALS Mentions book Man's Emerging Mind by N. J. Berrill.
    28 Nov. 1957 - TLS Comments at length on book of Emily Dickinson letters.
    29 Nov. 1957 - ALS Comments further on Emily Dickinson letters.
    3 Dec. 1957 - ALS Discusses at length the relationships of Emily Dickinson and those around her.
    19 Dec. 1957 - TLS Comments on Hillyer review of Emily Dickinson letters prior to publication of same.
    27 Dec. 1957 - ALS Expresses desire to have Hillyer write further on importance of Browne, an associate of Emily Dickinson.